

■ seongmin@gatech.edu | # https://www.seongmin.xyz | To Seongmin Lee | Seongmin Lee | W @SeongminLee

Summary_

I'm a Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Georgia Tech, advised by Professor Polo Chau. My research aims to provide explanations and interpretations for various machine learning techniques based on visualization. I received my B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering from Seoul National University in February 2021.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Aug. 2021 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Graduated with Summa Cum Laude. Overall GPA: 3.91/4.0, Major GPA: 3.94/4.0

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

Busan, South Korea

Korea Science Academy of KAIST MATH AND SCIENCE SPECIALIZED HIGH SCHOOL

One year early entrance, Graduated with distinction in GPA

Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2016

Research Experience

Cisco Systems, Inc.

California, USA (Remote)

PHD INTERN

- May. 2022 Jul. 2022 · Mentor: Ali Payani
- Added machine learning explanation and visualization features to RAI, a (to be) open-sourced project for responsible AI. • Improve disentangled representation learning to yield more interpretable feature vector.

Polo Club of Data Science, Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug. 2021 - Present

- Advisor: Prof. Duen Horng (Polo) Chau
- · Member of the Polo Club of Data Science where we innovate scalable, interactive, and interpretable tools that amplify human's ability to understand and interact with billion-scale data and machine learning models.
- · Working on projects about providing explanations on misinformation websites, DNN bias detection and visualization, and DNN concept evo-

Data Mining Lab, Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

Undergraduate Research Internship

Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- · Advisor: Prof. U Kang
- Studied multi-source domain adaptation under various constraints and settings
- Investigated the problem of BERT that the tasks with few training data are hard to fine-tune and solved it using reinforcement learning

Communication and Machine Learning Laboratory, Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea Sep. 2019 - Apr. 2020

Undergraduate Research Internship and Bachelor's Thesis

· Advisor: Prof. Jungwoo Lee

• Studied the problem of class imbalance and uncertainty in semantic segmentation

Biomedical Precision Laboratory, The University of Tokyo

Tokyo, Japan

Undergraduate Research Internship

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Advisor: Dr. Keiichi Nakagawa, Dr. Ayumu Ishijima.
- · Observed interaction between human cells and acoustic waves by constructing a microscopic motion-picture camera with sub-nano resolution using optical equipment and laser

SEONGMIN LEE · RÉSUMÉ OCTOBER 23, 2022

Publications

Explaining Website Reliability by Visualizing Hyperlink Connectivity

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, and Duen Horng (Polo) Chau IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS), 2022

NOVA: A Practical Method for Creating Notebook-Ready Visual Analytics

Zijie J. Wang, David Munechika, **Seongmin Lee**, and Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS), 2022

VisCUIT: Visual Auditor for Bias in CNN Image Classifier

Seongmin Lee, Zijie J. Wang, Judy Hoffman, and Duen Horng Chau

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022

MisVis: Explaining Web Misinformation Connections via Visual Summary

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, and Duen Horng Chau

CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts, 2022

Multi-EPL: Accurate Multi-Source Domain Adaptation

Seongmin Lee, Hyunsik Jeon, and U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

AUBER: Automated BERT Regularization

Hyun Dong Lee*, **Seongmin Lee***, and U Kang (* These authors contributed equally to this work)

Unsupervised Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with No Observable Source Data

Hyunsik Jeon, Seongmin Lee, and U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

Patent

Pruning Method for Attention Head in Transformer Neural Networks for Regularization and Apparatus Thereof

Seongmin Lee, Hyun Dong Lee, and U Kang

10-2020-0162397, 2020

Honors & Awards

The Presidential Science Scholarship

Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2019

KOREA SCIENCE AID FOUNDATION

SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)

Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, SNU

Voluntary Service Award

Dec. 2018, Dec. 2017

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SNU

Teaching

Data and Visual Analytics (CSE 6242), Graduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2022

Deep Learning Course for LG Chem, Lab session lecturer **Deep Learning Course for SK Hynix**, Lab session lecturer

Jan. 2021

Introduction to Algorithm, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor

Nov. 2020 Fall 2020, Fall 2019

Coming 2017

Introduction to Physics I, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor

Spring 2017

Skills_____

Programming C/C++, Python, Java, Verilog, HTML/CSS/Javascript

Frameworks Tensorflow, PyTorch

Languages Korean (Native), English (iBT: 109 (R28/L28/S26/W27), GRE: Verbal 163, Writing 4.5)

Extracurricular Activity _____

GTKSA (Georgia Tech Korean Student Association)	Aug. 2021 - Present
Serving as a secretary and web administrator.	
SNU Buddy	Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2020
Buddy program for the international exchange students. Used to be a group leader.	
SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)	Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019
Organized academic seminars, international round table, and mentoring programs as a vice president.	
Vision Mentoring, Seoul National University	Jul. 2019
Lectured high school students on engineering (More than 700 students attended)	
Dream Camp Mentoring, Seoul National University	Feb. 2019, Feb. 2018
Educated high school students in the countryside by designing a mentoring program	
Student Vice President	Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018
Elected as a vice president of the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, SNU	
Student Reporter	Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2021
Published brochures about the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering every semester	
Talent Sharing Volunteer Camp, KOSAF	Jan. 2017, Aug. 2016

Conducted self-planned mentoring for elementary school students in underprivileged areas in Korea